# Leonid Vlasov, Scala Software Engineer

leoniv.vlasov@gmail.com | Novosibirsk, Russia

https://www.linkedin.com/in/leoniv/ | https://github.com/leoniv

**SUMMARY** 

Professional software engineer with 15 year of experience and ability to solve challenging problems in the software development field. I am good at working in a team and I consider myself as a responsible, hard-working and ambitious specialist. I am on the top of up to date technologies, tools and the best practice which are taken by the software professionals' community.

**EXPERIENCE** 

## Eldis-soft, Scala Software engineer

2020-04-30 — Present

- I worked as a back-end Scala developer and a project lead. Our team created business services and single-page web applications based on REST. Nothing unusual, but we used a functional approach, particularly Scala with Cats.
- o Functional programming
- Scala
- Cats
- doobie
- o fs2
- o http4s
- PostgreSQL
- o Java

## FG BCS, Senior Software Engineer

2018-04-30 - 2020-04-30

- I worked as a senior engineer in a system integration team. BCS is the biggest Russian stockbroker with a developed and high-loaded information system. My main responsibilities ware to develop integration utilities and to maintain of consistency of shared data types.
- System integration
- o 1C:Enterprise
- o High load
- o SOAP
- XML Schema Definition (XSD)
- REST
- SQL

## Siberian Investment Group, Senior Software Engineer

2012-01-31 — 2018-04-30

- I worked as a software developer and support software engineer mostly for an accounting subdivisions.
- o System integration
- 1C:Enterprise
- Ruby
- SQL
- Bash
- o Git

**EDUCATION** 

## **Bratsk State University**

2004-08-31 — 2007-12-31

Engineer's degree - Information Technology

SKILLS Back-End: Scala, SQL, Ruby, PostgreSQL, XSD, SOAP, Java

Scala: Cats, doobie, http4s, fs2, tapir, sbt

Software development: Functional programming, Test automation, CI/CD, Clean code

DevOps: Nix, GitLab/CI, Docker, Bash

LANGUAGES

Russian (Native Speaker), English (Professional Working)